and later they are you're waiting and
maybe you're in having some solutions or
what you have heard so far so welcome
can you hear me yes you hear me yeah um
hi everybody nice to meet you i'm here
in northwest connecticut on a beautiful
spring day so i imagine you all here
enjoying the sunshine in the birds on i
I think I'll start out by being
provocative it's not unlike me so that
way kind of get to know me and I i well
first of all I do want to say that I'm
launching a soul we call it
self-organizing learning experience
rather than a term eat recalled
self-organized learning environment so
we're emphasizing the process nature of
the experiment and more starting that
this in two weeks actually have an
eight-week program and so at the end of
the summer I'll have a lot more actual
practical things to say about our
experiment but what I would like to
offer this group is some kind of
provocative comments and it really I
didn't plan to start this way but the
conversation between leaf and Michelle
kind of reached in me and kind of
drawing it out so I would recommend a
strong self reflection about their peer
to peer movement chasing the knowledge
economy I think the knowledge economy is
kind of done and I think this is why
we're strategies that institutions are
making now I mean they're dumping all
their products you can say online
they're making everything free they have
these MOOCs they have basically if you
understand the mindset of a knowledge
entrepreneur they're saying these are
free they're not
they're not worth anything to us anymore
I mean this is these are provocative
statements I'm over emphasizing it and
so the question is you know what is what
is coming at us in the future what is
the imaginative leap that this community
should make in some of these experiments
in other words if we have a design
intent that isn't is is future forward
then we won't have this problem that
Michelle just said in the sense that
we're always racing against time and so
these are the kinds of questions we ask
here at all the law because we run a
process called insight practice and so
it in given this question in terms of so
let me make some distinctions for
example the knowledge economy right now
is based upon the organizing storage and
retrieval of known information right
what is known and machines are doing
that for us really really well and they
will probably be doing all of that for
us in the very near future so this is
what Einstein predicted so this is
becoming a less and less of a value and
I think that's why institutions and
governments don't care if there's MOOCs
and all this stuff I mean they're they
don't want to chase something that's
being so quickly devalued its devalue
just like everything else is because
robots and machines are going to take
care of her better so the question is
what do we want to do you know engage
people that have the values of this
community into creating the future
through these kinds of nishat evoke ille
centers of Education I mean I agree with
many of you you know we're not trying to
get institutional affiliation we're
trying to start something as a living
center of the future of education here
at my home farm so that's I think a very
important question we answer in
different ways
we answer it in the sense that what we
think is the value in terms of the
newest fear is innovation and insight
insightful ideas complete paradigm shift
and so so that would be something that I
would suggest those of you that are
working on new schools to really take a
good look at what are the capacities
what are the capacities that this
generation needs and I think these are
capacities all around the world and they
take different forms so an insight or a
paradigm shift in Ecuador Africa maybe
more like solving this transportation to
value problem in another area it might
be coming up with what I call the fourth
the third term in economics so that's
one of the things for example we're
looking at there's assets liabilities
and then there's a third term that
should be incorporated in economics so
these are big ideas they're easy to
design I think that they are this for me
is what we should be designing education
for in the future and then the second
and I think that plays into some of what
Leif was asking about futures and the
second thing I just want to say is um
there's a sense in which and we could
all have a long discussion about this
but in terms of talking about the
comments and if we talk about knowledge
as a Commons again when I hear that
phrase I think of it as something you
know known what is known is is should be
accessible and I think that's true we
need universal access to the external
storage networks of what is known but
what is the concept of Commons with
relative to what is not known relative
to the
generation of new ideas the generation
of designs for the future of our our
children what's the definition of
Commons there and so I think we get it
gets a little tricky because all of our
definitions appear to appear in comments
are actually an obstacle to thinking
into the terms of those and so the work
we're doing makes a distinction between
peer-to-peer which is in many cases
understood as universal access to a
comments and then the and then the
interactions are static you know so you
interact with the commons and then
something comes back and stuff like that
versus true participatory interactions
where the known external network is just
a box you can draw from and to have
truly participatory commons means that
these Commons are enacted in real time
by participation and so those are kind
of like two big ideas I just wanted to
throw out there to give you an idea of
what I would hope is a valuable
contribution to the conversation
brilliant colors and philly kami yes yes
I can so where are you now are you nice
round yeah back in bangla in ballast ah
ok and I I really really today I loved
it these discussions for it especially
what was petit of bringing up we have
been pretty much working exactly with
that how can we will see like knowledge
or like education just being like based
on knowledge but William unlike on
experience and experience in systems and
fields forever everybody can participate
it should be included in a way of that
everybody already brings a lot of
knowledge and a lot of skills that is
needed in any terms and it's also the
way how is
or what we were very much realized over
the last two three four years is that we
also have now right now a very much a
cache of generations so a generation
which is now still in is very much
socialized very much educated with
within an education system that is a
pretty much in on a competitive based on
on a waste of like roofing that what you
know that that's that's that
you you compete with wisps around you in
order to show that it's the best
solution i'm i'm i'm not sure if there
is really a bad pollution in various
going yeah might not be just a bottom-up
and top-down approach in order to change
the education system in our networked
society will come from many places admit
that the same time with sinner where
you'll see different ways of credit
which will be very erotic and in in
order of really like getting the the
experience or left the opportunity to
deal with this change and to be able to
very often we also have the feeling that
we have to create a change and I hardly
believe that we created change we will
be part of the change will be part of
the transformation and I'll get for us
it's it very much about due to
understand how do we get the experience
to not being overrun by this information
which is coming up and this is what we
see very much in the flesh of
generations young kids around 20 kids
people the new generation around 20 to
23 years old you very often are not so
interested in in those discussions is
this a comment is it not is it who does
it belong to who do I trust they have a
very nature of many many people we work
with a very natural very CENTAC form of
trust of immediate trust to do people
and this is to what i see is very much
in our networked society that we
understand the level of trust it's not
only by our needs or what receives
visible but also but your your inner
strength you're in a way of of Louie
you're in strength you're in your will
of really being able to tap in the
unknown in the way of food like being
able to to economy knowledge and and
information around you very quickly and
knowing that you there's so much out
there that you will not handle it but in
a way that you have really also the
trust inside yourself trust further and
I think this is also very much needed in
participatory processes that it will not
always happen that we want to do not
obvious i have what happened like we
plan to if you look back in the best and
if we did look back in in the history
and see okay this is how it worked we
are knowing in inspiration we are
knowing it in a time of history where we
all as a collective can liberate it and
can be free whenever we act leave live
learn deal and this is a very very rural
area this is f not experienced so far
source also my my point of view so this
is flying okay how can we do better go
into the 50 unknown and have kind of the
confidence that we don't know where
every way leads us many people have
these variables to do but none of us can
really see what how far they did the
future but the future will bring us
we're but bleep button with what we are
doing now in in in perception the NGO
that we're order foundation or whatever
you would call it is Benedict long since
our system is the eater of this type of
organization form we are looking at
education systems and environment
schools in tubes on side or additional
ways of of tea and learn and we we
connect with our new forms of learning
there
we're traveling around we are making a
happen or we also invite communities
exactly around those environments to
form themselves very celebratory and in
that way we very often don't need to
plan how things should look like we just
have to look back and reflect okay what
what happened what Burke and what what
did we learn from our the last two steps
in order to make the next step we very
often think we already have to know the
form the fifth level this I think this
is in our times it it's very very
challenging very uh yeah kind of crazy
and so I think there have been many many
with good examples where an order
alternatives of Education are working
there are really new forms many of the
young generation they even don't they
don't need a university degree or they
don't need at the university experience
because they want to create their own
own education I think this this is the
very it's a very possible and we start
to really create their own personal
education and this is not related to
degrees this is not related to any
industry this is not related to any
economy because we we are becoming bar
off of yeah I see it really very much
the new generation where you can live on
ourselves very much and this is what you
can see now in person what's going on
this is also what you can see in in
various forms in Palestine which is very
much impressed with which is very much
uniform are you know under the
occupation usually a funny thing is and
if I need many places all around the
world the people are really breaking up
and getting out of the of the normal and
so yeah I got just needs a little bit
sense to all of you aspirin welcome to
the future okay stop lying and welcome
see can you hear me ok just not thank
you ok well I just have a few comments
here well first I'm going to try to grow
my hair style the same as those in
firenzi and I hope that it can be and
that level by the time i get there this
summer so i'm working on it the beard i
don't know i will try maybe that's part
of the cake Oien process that we have to
do here I work as a fellow at the PTP
foundation and also a professor at
Sydney on university women's university
and sold at for digital humanities um I
have a couple comments here that first
of all I start with that that p2p as I
see it is the productive capacity of
civil society so for example you know
governments States NGOs the military the
capitalist sector corporations all can
produce pharmaceuticals and cars
satellites biomedical equipment that but
civil society up to this point has only
been able to be involved in political
protest it has been very powerful as you
know but it hasn't been able to produce
say pharmaceuticals so when Africa tried
to in 2001 whenever to try to produce
their own pharmaceuticals and then the
consortium of pharmaceutical companies
block them there is no other outlet
African governments to produce keeper
drugs for AIDS patients so how do we
build a knowledge base for commons that
can have productive capacity come out of
that and things like pharmaceuticals and
other things that we need so that's one
thesis there I think that
the edgy no future foundation is working
there in Ecuador that Michelle talked
about a moto what what he is doing there
is this basically you have a country
that has plenty of natural resources
that are exploited and shipped out that
they can leverage that wealth to move
from savory industrialization over at
the knowledge economy and if you have
free libre and open knowledge that term
means for plot society then indeed I
think that it is possible for them over
quickly I mean if countries don't mean
if China doesn't do this a South Korea
doesn't do it or and Japan there's going
to be major societies in decline so I
can speak about East Asia where I met
moment one thing but in that case in
Ecuador it's the similar kind of thing
they can leverage that well that they
have move into a better structure and at
the base of all of us is knowledge just
as lief said earlier about the reverse
its eight hundred years ago but in leaf
I'd like to get some more references to
that later on what Bonnie said a moment
ago amount of access to the Commons as
being different than necessarily p2p
productive capacity is interesting
because we do need to have universal
access to a comments such that no one's
left out but that doesn't mean that on
top of that calm comes that assisted
reproductive professor our productive
communities as Michelle calls it could
me I mean they could be built on top of
that to make my own biomedical products
educational products and so on and so
could a capitalist economy here Jeremy
Rifkin talks about so so I think that
all of these things are compatible as
long as we have that fundamental basis
of the Commons and Michelle can talk
more about that at the moment as Horace
commenting around the knowledge and
education stuff here the historian who
killed human is a colleague of mine he's
the founder of this career center for
digital be managed
he's working to make the world's
knowledge available to students here in
Korea in higher education and then of
course moving on to other sectors of
education of the children and then for
the rest of Asia there's a moat plant
find open courses platform that's the
beginning of this and as they hang out
with Bonnie last night she and I
discussed this and then what's the next
generation of more simplexity she calls
it for education and I think that
perhaps she and uncle Kim can talk
sometime about that finally I want to
make a comment about what we're facing
in the near future and I'm very cautious
to speak about the future beyond say
five or ten years specifically for what
Michelle talked about is the in 20-30 we
this kind of perfect storm he mentioned
is something that the physicists are
saying we can't see beyond what would it
what it means is that the
complexification though things will be
to a point that we can't even predict
beyond that so whenever you see a
government say in 2050 the population
will be x + sr it totally alone
assistive and so I think that salvitore
is concept here of the near future is
the best that we can do for anything not
just for education but in the case of
education what we see happening is if
you think about how much data and
information is produced each day
probably since that maybe in nineteen
eighty more informations been produced
than ever in the history of humankind
and that will become yearly and then
every six months every three months and
perhaps even daily more information
produced than was before nineteen eighty
if you can get an idea this it's not
going to be possible to process that
data so what we thinks going to have to
happen is they're going to have to be
algorithms that we set up that will
interpret the real world for us and then
we're going to need convergence groups
that will that can facilitate the
education of students so I call these
convergence teams or convergence groups
and they have to have what what they
used to call multidisciplinary studies
of what we is called convergence today
working together to try to make sense of
momentum explosion of data and
information so incidentally we just
released a white paper today on the
tragedy of Fukushima and the failure of
the technological system and that was a
p2p organized process that began in
September there was a knowledge open
knowledge process there were 28
researchers involved and then the white
paper something like eighty seven pages
with and half for phones so that's one
example that we have from p2p foundation
and the Asian Institute and I'll end up
here with the fact that I not only on
how should I say like like Bonnie says
what was done in the past for education
is over the whole thing about organizing
and storing data and all that stuff
that's done by machines how will we
facilitate learning from here on using
machines as necessary and so that might
be my question to you guys and then how
will it come about that both the
universalized access to commons and then
ttp structures that will enter in maybe
with the cake oien like the debate that
went on this week so I'll I'll in there
and thanks a lot or all of you being
here it's so nice to see you all so
thanks very much there so we can take
some small comments or reflections there
there was a great many questions here on
thought so we have a lot to discuss this
but leave it open here for a shoot few
reflections I just I'll make a comment
and maybe it could be a wrap up to so
you know when elaine was talking I was
thinking about knowledge is becoming too
big to know
you know and and this is especially true
as we all work toward distributed forms
of knowledge right i mean we're actually
nahmias knowledge being created too fast
to kind of capture it but we're all
working toward distributed knowledge and
that's going to ask you know make this
problem or opportunity even greater that
knowledge is too big to know so um I
think and then the other thing is you
know when I forgot how you frame the
question lane but so what do what do
young people need you know what young
people are intuitively aware that they
are now facing an unknown and unknowable
future I mean this is this is you speak
to them and you go to workshops and this
is what's definitely inside of them so
what you know so it's for me it's like
we can provide them is navigation tools
now what kind of navigation tools I
don't think we provide them content we
provide them navigation tools and even
then we have to be humble because these
we need to listen to the structure of
their evolving lines for the kinds of
you know navigation tools they need for
where they only don't know they know
where they're going you know I like to
tell the story the march of the penguins
you know after the mother has changed
the egg to the father and the father
changed the eggs to the mothers and then
they all go out feed the new babies are
sitting there in Antarctica waiting and
waiting and waiting and you know what
the parents aren't coming back and I
tell young people this all the time your
parents aren't coming back that's just
the truth of it in a future that moves
this fast and so we need to look for
natural born leaders coming from that
generation and learn to listen bar
current work continue to listen for
educators into the future that's already
been born in some sense to them so that
would be kind of my comment and my
reflection so I think thanks
you